After we have learned about the hip sword algorithm, let's learn about its complexity and discover
that time complexity and the space complexity.
The hip sort algorithm come time complexity and the best case and look in the worst case is endless
again.
And the average case is and again, let's understand the reason why the heart of a complete binary tree
containing any elements is loug end.
And we have proved it in the binary search threes and the complete binary threes in the previous videos.
So as we have seen earlier, to fully typify an element whose sub trees are ready max heaps, we need
to keep comparing the elements with its left and right children and pushing it downwards until it reaches
a point where both its children are smaller than it.
And this worst case scenario, we will need to move an element from their route to their leaf nodes,
making a multiple of and or two log and comparisons and swaps.
So during the build max heap stage that we have done it.
We do that and over two elements so that the worst case complexity of the build a hit step is and over
two times longer and which has meaning and look n and the during the average time, it's the same.
So also it performs like also since the build max heap and the heap sort steps are executed one after
another.
The algorithmic complexity is not multiplied and it remains in the order of and Logan.
So this is what the reason behind the time complexity in the best worse than the average.
In terms of space complexity, also the heap sort algorithm performs, sorting in all one space complex
compared with quick sort is it has a better worst case scenario, which is and look and the quick sort
has complexity all and power do for worst case.
But in other cases, quick sort is fast and sort is an alternative to hips or that combines quick sort.
And he it's hard to retain the advantages of both the worst case speed of hip sort and the average speed
of quick sort.
So this stability is not the stable algorithm, and we like to make to use that many, many algorithms
better than a quick sort and merge sort.
Now let's move to the C language implementation of the hip sort algorithm and later on that solve them
exercise to implement.